(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-29T21:18:26.484274",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
みんなー！
Everyone!
こんばんはー！
Good evening!
どなただー？
Who could it be?
ホロライブ4期生 角巻わためです！
I'm Tsunomaki Watame, Hololive 4th Gen!
今日はね、寒気にもあるんだけどね、
Today, well, there's a cold snap too, but...
重大告知がね、あるみたいで、
it seems there's a major announcement,
でもわためわかんない、なんだろうね。
but Watame has no idea what it could be.
でもねわかんないんだけどね、その代わりに、なぜか今日はいろんな方から呼び出しをね、受けててさ。
Even though I don't know, instead, for some reason today I'm getting called out by various people.
受けててさ、
Getting called out,
知らないんだよ、ねー！
and I don't even know, you know!
重大告知と関係あんのかねー？
Could it be related to the major announcement?
どうなんだろうね。
I wonder what it is.
あ、今日はこんな感じで、まったりのんびりやっていきますよ。
Ah, today I'll be going at it in a relaxed, leisurely way.
たまにはね、3Dでのんびり配信しても悪くないよ、にーー！
Sometimes, doing a leisurely 3D stream isn't bad either, yeeeah!
ちょっとね、まだね、呼び出しの待ち時間まで時間があるっぽいから、お話ししますからみんなと。
Wait, since there seems to be still some time until the call-out, I'll chat with you all.
お話ししますかな？
Shall we chat?
みんな見えてる？
Can everyone see me?
見えてる？
Can you see me?
すごいね、コメントの速度、すっごーい！
Wow, the speed of the comments is amazing!
みんなねー、って言ってる。
Everyone's saying "Hey" etc.
え、なんだと思う？
Eh, what do you think it is?
今日のみんな、なんだと思う？
What do you guys think today's announcement is?
わためわかんないんだけどさ、
Watame has no idea, but...
あの、もう1ミリもわかんないんだけどさ、なんだと思う？
Um, I don't know even by a millimeter, what do you think?
今までのわため史上最大で、え、なんだっけ？
The biggest in Watame's history so far, um, what was it?
最高で、最強の、重大告知って言ってたっけ？
The best, strongest major announcement, did she say?
告白とか、ジェネシスカンタービレ？
Confession or Genesis Cantabile?
最後の晩餐なの、今日？
Is today's the Last Supper?
あれ、おかしいな。
Huh, that's strange.
怖いな、もっといいお話だったと思うんだけどね。
It's scary, I thought it was a much nicer story.
あ、わかんないけどね、
Ah, I don't know though,
何のことか分からんけどね。
I have no idea what it's about.
わためや。
Watame-ya.
は？
Huh?
わためや。
Watame-ya.
誰だ？
Who is it?
ボタンちゃん？
Botan-chan?
獅子白ボタンじゃよ。
It's Shishiro Botan.
え、なんかせんえんみたいになって
Eh, you look like a hermit...
神様になったの？
Did you become a god?
獅白ぼたんデス。
I am Shishiro Botan.
獅白ぼたんです。
おら。
Hey.
ようこそ。
Welcome.
今日はわため呼び出してどうするつもりだ？
What do you plan to do calling Watame out today?
パーティー？ジンギスカンパーティーなのかな？
A party? A Genghis Khan party, I wonder?
出荷でもしようかな？
Shall I ship you off?
おかしいよ！
That's crazy!
ま、待て待て待て、こんなね、おろおろしい登場しましたけれども、
Wait, wait, wait, although I made such a spooky entrance,
ま、今日は特に何もないですよ。
well, today there's nothing special in particular.
ただね、ちょっとね、わためとちょっとゆっくりお話ししたいなと思って、
Just that, well, I thought I wanted to chat leisurely with Watame,
今日はちょっとここにね、
so today I came to hang out here,
わためのかくれがに遊びに来たわけですよ。
in Watame's hideout.
あ、そうね。
Ah, right.
ここ隠れ家だもんね。
This is a hideout, after all.
もう、もう道覚えちゃったからね。
Already, I've memorized the path.
逃げれねえからな。
You can't escape, you know.
こわー！
Scary!
いや、今日は何もないんだもんね？
No, today there's nothing, right?
うん、何もない。
Yeah, nothing.
ないない。
None, none.
うん、ないない。
Yeah, none, none.
ゆっくりお話しするだけ。
Just chatting leisurely.
うん、ゆっくり。
Yeah, leisurely.
何かなげた？
Did you throw something?
あ、気にしないで。
Ah, don't worry about it.
あの、今日の天気、あの、今日の天気、あの、晴れの時々手榴弾だから。
Um, today's weather, um, today's weather, um, it's sunny with occasional hand grenades.
晴れの時々手榴弾？
Sunny with occasional hand grenades?
気にしないで。
Don't worry about it.
え、雨だけじゃなくて？
Eh, not just rain?
手榴弾ふってくるなんてきたの？
Hand grenades falling came up?
まあ、そんな日もあると思う。
Well, I think there are days like that too.
どうかな？
I wonder?
まあ、最近ちょっと異常気象だしね。
Well, lately the weather's been a bit abnormal.
そうそう。
That's right.
いっ、ちょっと待てん。
Wait, wait a second.
あると思うんだ。
I think there is.
なるほどね。
I see.
無きにしもあらずってことかな、じゃあ？
Does that mean it's not out of the question? Then...
当たんねえな。
It's not hitting.
うん。
Yeah.
なんて？ただいま。
What? I'm back.
あ、ごめん。なんて？
Ah, sorry. What?
なんでもない、なんでもない。
It's nothing, nothing.
今かすった、かすった！かすったよ、今！
It grazed me, it grazed me! It grazed me just now!
かすったか。惜しいな。
Grazed? Too bad.
いてっ！これお風呂しみるやつ。
Ouch! This is gonna sting in the bath.
でも、ボタンちゃんが巡航ミサイル投げてくるんだったら、
But if Botan-chan is going to throw cruise missiles at me,
わためだって負けないんだぜ！
Watame isn't going to lose!
お？なに見てんだ？
Hm? What are you looking at?
みたいなおしゃれな、ほら！
Like some stylish... look!
射撃！
Shooting!
結構狙ってる！
I'm aiming well!
片手で撃ってやる！
I'll shoot you with one hand!
あえて片手で撃ってやる！
I'll dare to shoot with one hand!
反動もないぜ！
There's no recoil either!
本当だ。
True.
反動もねえ、なんてこと…
No recoil at all, what...
じゃあね、ま、そんなこんなでね、じゃあどうしようかな。
Well then, anyway, what should I do now?
今から、じゃあ3分ぐらいちょっと雑談して、あの、終わったころにわためが無事だったら、
From now on, let's chat for about 3 minutes, and if Watame is safe by the end of it...
あの、今日重大告知あるらしいじゃない？
Um, isn't there a major announcement today?
それに関する秘密のキーワードを私情が教えてあげます、ひとつ。
I will teach you one secret keyword regarding that, myself.
何？キーワード？
What? A keyword?
キーワードです。オッケー。
It's a keyword. Okay.
じゃあ何話しましょう？なんか、なんか飲んでくぐれるような、遠くテーマがいいかなと、思うんですけど。
So what should we talk about? I think a distant theme where we can relax would be good.
何がいいかな？これって重いんだ。重いんだね、これ。
What would be good? This is heavy. It's heavy, isn't it?
結構重いし、が片手であげてたけど、重いんだね！
I was holding it with one hand, but it's heavy!
でも、まあさっきも言った通り、まあトークをせず3分間生き残ったらってことなので、
But well, as I said earlier, since the goal is to survive for 3 minutes without talking—
あ、トークせずちょっと避けてください。
Ah, please avoid talking.
わかりました。
Understood.
はい、で、わため夏休み何、何かやってます？
Well, Watame, are you doing anything for summer vacation?
休みなんてねえ！
There's no vacation!
ああ、結構忙しいんだね。休みある？
Ah, you're quite busy. Do you have days off?
なんか休んだ？うーん、特になんか休んだ記憶ねえな。
Did you rest? Hmm, I don't really remember resting much.
ねえよな。あの、ほら、あの、ちょっと私、1周年だったもので。
Right? Also, you see, it was my 1st anniversary.
あ、そうなんだね。そうそうわためもね、ありがとね、来てくれてね。
Ah, is that so. That's right, Watame, thanks for coming.
いや、呼んでくれてありがとうね。誕生日とか、え？
No, thank you for inviting me. Birthday or... wait,
近くなかったっけ？まだ忙しいんだよね。
wasn't it close? You're still busy though.
まだちょっと忙しいんだけどね。
I'm still a bit busy.
でもね、わためさんのお誕生日もね、私呼んでいただけて嬉しかったです。
But I was happy you invited me to Watame-san's birthday as well.
またよ、呼ぶよ。
I'll invite you again.
ありがとうね。だから遊んでよ。暇だったら遊んだよ。
Thank you. So let's hang out. If you're free, let's hang out.
またやろう、ふらせ。これふらせれんののかな？もっとふらせれんののかな？
Let's do it again, make it rain. Can I make it rain more?
過激派だな。
You're radical.
や、ここさ、わための一家が広いからね。そうね。ちょっと先やすいいよね。
Well, Watame's family home is big, you see. Right. It's a bit dangerous ahead.
危ね！あ、なんか
Watch out! Ah, sort of
なんかね、今でもコメントで今当たったよってコメントありますけど、当たりました？
Um, there's a comment saying "you got hit just now," did I get hit?
当たってないよな！
I didn't get hit!
当たってないよなああああ！
I didn't get hit at allllll!
当たって、当たってって、当たってないよなお父さん、ちょっと待て！
Hit! Hit, I didn't get hit, wait a second!
でも、大丈夫だ。
But it's fine.
え？なんか痛くなってきたかもしれない。あれ、なんか痛い！
Huh? It might have started hurting. Huh, it hurts!
生き延びればいいのだろう？
All I have to do is survive, right?
なに、終わったよ！もう10分も経ってないのに！終わったよ！
What, it's over! Even though 10 minutes haven't passed! It's over!
生き延びればいいんでしょ、怪我してもね。
It's fine as long as I survive, even if I'm injured.
まあね。うまいんだよ。怖いね。
Well, yeah. She's good. Scary.
何のごん？しきっしょ！押し迷、
What kind of... damn it!
やばい、無事、はい、無事生き残りました。おめでとうございます。コングラチュレーション！
Oh no, safely... yes, I survived safely. Congratulations. Congratulations!
いや、コングラチュレーション！やったあああ！出ない、だだだだだ、やったあ！
Congratulations! Yayyy! It won't come out, da-da-da-da, yay!
まあね、わためが無事でよかったよ。本当に良かった。
Well, I'm glad Watame is safe. Really glad.
危な、なんか当たったんじゃねえかって言われたけど。ま、大丈夫だ、生きてるから大丈夫だ。
Scary, they said I might have gotten hit. Well, it's fine, I'm alive so it's fine.
楽しかった。これちゃんと言えたかな？
It was fun. Did I say that properly?
じゃあね、あの、わためにとね、約束通り重大告知に関わる、お、キーワードを教えてあげる。
Well then, as promised, I'll tell Watame the keyword related to the major announcement.
何々？いいよ。
What what? Okay.
じゃあ、あの、リスナーの皆さんもね、キーワードを1つ教えます。
Well, I'll teach the listeners one keyword too.
キーワードは、数字の6です。
The keyword is the number 6.
6？6です。
6? It's 6.
6？なんだ？わかんないな。
6? What is this? I don't get it.
まあね、あの、時期わかると思うので、ま、これからのもちょっとキーワードを集めてよ。
Well, you'll figure out the timing, so gather keywords from here on too.
わかった。頑張るわ。
Understood. I'll do my best.
のんびり
Taking it easy...
綿めや頑張るのじゃぞ
Watame-ya, do your best!
ありがとうボタン神様ありがとうございます
Thank you, Button God, thank you so much!
これじゃうちはこの辺で
Well then, I'll be around here.
またな
See you later!
またな、危ない危ない
See you later! Careful, careful.
危ねえ危ねえ
That was close, that was close.
なんだろね
I wonder what that is.
ボタンちゃんありがとう
Thank you, Button-chan!
6ってなんだろうね
What does "6" mean, I wonder?
とりあえずこの装備外しておこうかぶそうだからね
Let's take this equipment off first, since it looks dangerous.
よいしょっと
There we go.
みんなわかる？なんだろうね
Does everyone get it? What could it be?
え、まさかロッキーさん？いや
Huh, could it be Rocky-san? No...
綿めがそんな重大な
Watame doing something so major—
あ、あぴぴ！あぴぴぴ！
Ah, Apipi! Apipipi!
あ、なんだ？角で何にか動画を受信したぞびぴぴぴぴぴぴぴ
Ah, what's this? My horns received some kind of video message, bipipipipipipi!
なんだ？
What is this?
綿め先輩こんばんは！
Watame-senpai, good evening!
Hololive English Myth's Calliope Mori here. 先輩元気ですか？
Hololive English Myth's Calliope Mori here. Senpai, how are you?
今は私ね旅行中ですが今夜綿め先輩においしたいと思いました
I'm currently traveling right now, but I wanted to greet Watame-senpai tonight.
綿め先輩の歌声すごく素敵だよ！最高の音楽ありがとうございます
Watame-senpai's singing voice is so wonderful! Thank you for the amazing music.
いつも聞いていますよよかったらぜひまたコラボしたいよね
I always listen to it! I'd love for us to collab again sometime if you'd like.
その時まで私ね綿め先輩の活動をよく見るつもりですよろしくね
Until then, I plan on keeping a close eye on Watame-senpai's activities. Nice to work with you!
私からの挑戦をクリアできたらキーワードを教えてあげます
If you can clear my challenge, I'll give you a keyword.
チャレンジは今から1分間英語で自己紹介と趣味と自分の好きなことを語ってください
The challenge is: for the next 1 minute, please introduce yourself, your hobbies, and things you like in English!
日本語使ったらアウトですよ
If you use Japanese, you're out!
それでは綿め先輩頑張ってください！ばいばい
Well then, Watame-senpai, do your best! Bye-bye!
カリオペちゃんありがとう！ありがとうだけど
Thank you, Calliope-chan! Thank you, but...
英語でなんか言い言って言ってたね
She said to say something in English, didn't she?
やってみようかチャレンジしてみっかかな
Should I try it? Should I give the challenge a try?
あ、そうやでもね綿めもちょっとよ、ラッパーっぽい！よーい！よーい！サングラス持ってんの、それつけてもいい？いい？
Oh, right! But you know, Watame is kinda... like a rapper! Yo-i! Yo-i! I have star sunglasses, can I put them on? Is that okay? Is that okay?
コスプレ？コスプレしてもいい？ちょっとつけるわ
Cosplay? Can I cosplay too? I'll put them on.
あ、ほら！チェキーン！ちょっとね、あの
Ah, look! Shing! Wait, um...
刀なかったから斧でもいいかな？刀なかったからさ
Since I didn't have a katana, I guess an axe is fine? Since I didn't have a katana...
斧で頑張る、ちょっとカリオペちゃんをイメージして頑張ります
I'll do my best with an axe, imagining Calliope-chan, I'll do my best!
では、チャレンジ、スタートターン！
Now then, challenge, start-turn!
マイネームイズ、綿め角巻キー
My name is... Watame Tsunomaki!
マイホビーイズ、マイホビーイズ、シェアハッピー…
My hobby is... my hobby is... um...
メステローイエイ！メステローイエイ！
Me tello! Yay! Me tello! Yay!
アイライクシンガソング！アイライクシンガソング！
I like singer song... I like singer song!
ファニーダンス！ファニーダンス！
Uh, funny dance! Funny dance!
ファニーダンス！うーん…
Uh, funny dance! Uh...
アイライクアップル…
I like apple...
アイライクパイナップル！
I like pineapple!
アイライクピニャータタイム！イエイ！
I like Pinata time! Yay!
アイライクゲームアンドストーリータイム！イエイ！グッドモーニングマンドリング！イエイ！サンキュー！
I like game and storytelling! Yay! Good morning, mandorying! Yay! Thank you!
はい、パーフェクト！はい、カムペキ！
Yup, perfect! Yup, flawless!
これはクリアだよね？ねえ！
This is cleared, right? Hey!
ハローハローアゲイン！わあ、ナイスジョブ先輩！
Hello, hello again! Wow, nice job, senpai!
英語上手！Your English is really great! You are amazing!
Your English is really great! You are amazing!
I want to teach you English someday. Please help me with my Japanese!
オーケーオーケー、それではキーワードのプレゼントです！キーワードは「I」です！
Okay, okay! Now, here is your present of the keyword! The keyword is "I"!
先輩またね、がんばって！
Senpai, see you again, do your best!
英語の、アイ！？
English... "I"!?
数字の次は英語か！謎だな、わかんないね、6とIってなんだろうね
The next one after a number is English! It's a mystery, I don't get it. What are 6 and I, I wonder?
カリオペちゃん、ありがとうね！
Calliope-chan, thank you!
なんか今回ね、この角でね受信できるようになりました
Somehow this time, I became able to receive it through these horns!
新しい能力を身につけました！イエーイ！
I've acquired a brand-new ability! Yay!
この穴めっちゃ重かったなー！
This hole was so heavy!
よいしょっと。
Heave-ho.
あー重かったな、めっちゃ。
Ah, it was so heavy.
さてと…。
Now then...
これね、あとね3匹ぐらいにねちょっと呼び出されてるんだけどね、全くわためは
I was called out by about 3 others, but Watame completely...
ほら、わい人気モンだな！がっはっはっはっは！
"See? I'm quite popular!" Hahaha!
わーわーわーわーわーわーわー！わー！あたし！
Wa-wa-wa-wa-wa-wa-wa! Wow! Me!
イエーイ！
Yay!
あ、あ、もし？おねーさん、いんどねーしあ、いきするあやーに・よふぃてぃです！
Ah, hello? I am Airani Iofifteen from Indonesia!
よふぃちゃーん！
Iofi-chan!
もしかして、先輩！？
Could it be... a senior?!
よふぃもキーワードを背負い来てくれたの？
Did you come carrying a keyword too, Iofi?
あ、そうなの？
Ah, is that so?
そうなの！
That's right!
そう？
Really?
そう、もちろんタダでは教えませんよ。
Yes, of course I won't tell you for free.
えー、教えてよー！
Eh, tell me!
教えなーいです！
I won't tell you!
教えなさいよ！
Tell me!
私の一からのチャレンジは、絵のお題です！
My challenge from scratch is a drawing prompt!
絵のお題？
A drawing prompt?
そう、お絵かきですよ！
That's right, drawing!
じゃあちょっとね、わため画伯に変身するから待ってて。
Well then, wait a second while I transform into Master Painter Watame.
あ、了解です。
Ah, understood.
へえーっ！
Whoa!
セーフ！
Safe!
次！
Next!
えっ、ちょ、似てます？
Eh, wait, does it look like it?
似てる？
Does it?
え、絵下手さの？
Um, is my drawing bad?
えっ、絵描こう？
Uh, shall we draw?
イエーイ！
Yay!
じゃ、行けましょう！
Well then, let's go!
じゃあ、ちょっとこっち座るわ。
Well, I'll sit over here.
うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah.
あ、オッケー。
Ah, okay.
じゃあ、チャレンジの内容なんですがね、いおふぃがわため先輩にドローイングの指示を出します。
Now, for the challenge details, Iofi will give Watame-senpai drawing instructions.
で、いおふぃの指示通りに描いていただければとあるものになるので、自分の絵を見て、お題のものを当てられればチャレンジクリアということです！
And if you draw according to Iofi's instructions, it will become a certain something, so if you guess what the prompt is from your drawing, you clear the challenge!
オッケー！いおふぃの指示通りに描けばいいのね？それで筋道だけだと、ちょっと分かる絵だと思いますので、これで一旦練習問題に行きましょうか。
Okay! I just need to draw according to Iofi's instructions, right? I think that alone will make it recognizable, so let's try a practice question first.
オッケー！
Okay!
じゃあ、準備はいいですか？
Well, are you ready?
オッケー！
Okay!
いつでもかまいん。
Whenever you're ready.
じゃあ、まずは丸を描いてもらいます。
Well, first, please draw a circle.
丸？
A circle?
丸。
A circle.
適当にいいの？
Is anywhere fine?
そう、適当で、もう本当に大きいで も小さいでもなので大丈夫なので。
Yes, anywhere is fine, really, big or small is fine.
丸描いた？
Did you draw a circle?
オッケーで、その丸の上にアホ毛をつけます。一本で大丈夫なんだけど。
Okay, and on top of that circle, put an ahoge. One is fine.
アホ毛？
An ahoge?
え、アホ毛を、こういう感じでも大丈夫なんで。
Um, an ahoge like this is fine too.
こういうこと？
Like this?
そうそうそうそう！
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
アホ毛だよ。
An ahoge.
え！？一人しか頑張んないよ、これ。
Eh?! Only one person is trying here.
もうちょっと太い、太くしてもいいですか？
Can I make it a bit thicker?
そうそうそうそう！もうちょっともうちょっとアホ毛をもうちょっと、なんだろうね、ぷちゃっと、ぼしゃっと取って。
Yes, yes, yes! Make the ahoge a bit more, I wonder, squishy or fluffy.
こう？
Like this?
お？
Oh?
こういうこと？
Something like this?
なにこれ！？
What is this?!
え、そう！それ何だと思いますか？
Eh, yes! What do you think that is?
これ何これ！？
What in the world is this?!
何だと思いますか？
What do you think it is?
え？
Eh?
かぶ？
Turnip?
えっと、甘いんです。味は甘いですね。
Um, it's sweet. The taste is sweet.
甘い？
Sweet?
え、じゃあ甘い？
Eh, then it's sweet?
さっき好きなものと似てますよ、さっき。
It's similar to what you liked earlier.
あ、りんご？
Ah, apple?
あ、これりんご！
Ah, this is an apple!
正解です！
Correct!
あ、りんごだったのか！なるほど、ちょっとりんごに似てますね。これはりんごだったんだ！
Ah, so it was an apple! I see, it looks a bit like an apple. So it was an apple!
じゃあ、りんご。
Well then, an apple.
もう上図ですね。
You're quite skilled.
じゃあ、次カット文字は？
Well, next cut character?
うん。
Yeah.
あ、そう？
Ah, is that so?
一本で結構りんごに感じますよ。
With just one, it really feels like an apple.
オッケー！じゃあという事で、次は
Okay! Well then, next is...
本番ですよね？オッケー、本番ですよ。
The real deal, right? Okay, it's the real deal.
行きますよー？
Here we go?
オッケー。
Okay.
オッケー？
Okay?
オッケー！
Okay!
じゃあ！
Then!
行きましょう！
Let's go!
スタート！
Start!
まず、雲を描いてみます。
First, let's try drawing a cloud.
雲？もう本当にその雲はね、めっちゃもこもこにしてください。
A cloud? Really, make that cloud super fluffy.
もこもこ？
Fluffy?
そう、もこもこな雲ですよ。こう、もこもこおのんだばっかんな。
Yes, a fluffy cloud. Like, super fluffy.
柔らかな、そうそうそうそう。
Soft, yes, yes, yes, yes.
で、お？
And, oh?
入れるのかな？
Should I put it?
そう、で、真ん中に丸を2つです。
Yes, and two circles in the middle.
真ん中に丸を2つ？
Two circles in the middle?
そう、丸2つです。
Yes, two circles.
なんなこれ！？
What is this?!
えー、最後にっと左側と右側にちょっとうずまきっぽいを描いてみましょう。
Uh, finally, let's try drawing something like a whirlpool on the left and right sides.
どこどこどこ？うずまきどこ？
Where, where, where? Where's the whirlpool?
そうそう、あの、うずまき、なんだろうね、もこもこのあたりにその左側と
Yes, yes, around that fluffy part, on the left side and...
右側にうずまきをこう描いてみましょう。こう、ぷるぷるぷるぷる。
on the right side, let's draw a whirlpool like this. Like, wobbly wobbly.
こう？
Like this?
そうそうそう、上手にしても、もっとが
Yes, yes, yes, even if you do well, more...
もう一つ？あ、そうなの？
Another one? Oh, really?
なんて？
What?
じゃあ
Then...
何だと思いますか？
What do you think it is?
きっずじ！
Kid's ji!
やったー！
Yay!
おめでとうすごーい！キッズじクリアです！
Congratulations, amazing! Kid's ji clear!
やったー！クリアです！
Yay! Clear!
筋合ってたね。
It made sense.
筋合ってましたね。
心が？
My heart?
ということで、次チャレンジクリア！
So, next challenge clear!
キーワード、押しますか？押しますか？
Shall we press the keyword? Shall we?
お願いします！
Please!
では、キーワードは
Now, the keyword is...
そうです！ひらがなのそ！ひらがなのそ、ひらがなの
That's right! Hiragana 'so'! Hiragana 'so'...
そうですよ、ここにきてひらがな
That's right, coming here and hiragana...
なんだろう
I wonder what it is.
なんでしょうね！では今日はありがとうございました！
I wonder what! Well, thank you for today!
また遊びましょう！
Let's play again!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
お疲れ様でしたー！
Good job!
またねー！またねー！
See you! See you!
はい、スクショタイムですよって
Yes, it's screenshot time!
え、そ？
Eh, 'so'?
なんだろうね、ここにきてそか。わかるみんな？
I wonder what it is, 'so' coming here. Do you all get it?
６に、愛に、そ？わかんない
6, AI, so? I don't know.
まあでもね、わためが描く大活躍だったぜがはは！完璧だったね。
Well, but Watame's drawing was a huge success, gahahaha! It was perfect.
んな、今まで全部完璧だね。
Well, up until now everything has been perfect.
んな、んな
Nna, nna...
いやでも、今思ったけど、みんなこれわため先輩って、ねえ、後輩が来てくれて嬉しいね！
No, but I just thought, everyone, this Watame-senpai, hey, a junior came and I'm so happy!
わためもわかんない、みんな、みんなかんないって、わためもわかんない、なんだろう
Watame doesn't get it either, everyone doesn't get it, Watame doesn't get it either, I wonder what it is.
でも嬉しいね、先輩になったって思うと感慨深いなあ、あといくつあるんだろうね
But I'm happy, thinking I've become a senpai is profound, I wonder how many more there are.
わためちゃん！
Watame-chan!
はっ！
Ha!
この声は……どうも、ふみです。
This voice is... Hello, Fumi here.
ふみママ──！
Fumi-mama!
ついに──え──？もしかして重大発表って
Finally-- Eh? Could it be that the major announcement is...
ふみママが初めて配信に出る──ってこと？だったの？違うの？
that Fumi-mama is going on stream for the first time? Was it? Is it not?
重大発表はわためちゃんのことだよ？
The major announcement is about Watame-chan, you know?
え、そうなの、ふみママのことじゃないの？
Eh, is that so, isn't it about Fumi-mama?
そう、なんか重要、重大な任務を任されたので来たんだけど、何したらいいんだろ
Yeah, like, I was entrusted with a major mission and came, but I wonder what I should do.
なんだ、じゃあ、お話すればいいのかな？
What, then, should I just talk?
なんか配信したことない初心者が、そっか、すごい配信に来ちゃって大丈夫かな
A beginner who has never streamed before, I see, coming to such an amazing stream, will I be okay?
大丈夫だよ、みんな！いや、出てくれてまんなかった
It's alright, everyone! No, I'm so glad you came!
え、ちょっと、いらいな質問してもいい？ふみママに。
Eh, wait, can I ask a weird question? To Fumi-mama.
はい。ママに、じゃあ──なんだ、絵を描くきっかけは──なんだっけの？
Yes. To mama, then-- What was it, what triggered you to draw?
小さいころ、落書きはしてたんだけど、その、延長線上かな？
When I was little, I used to doodle, but I guess it's an extension of that?
はい、何歳ぐらいから？幼稚園とか？あら、ごちゃんいとか？そう。
Yes, around what age? Kindergarten? Or... yeah.
じゃあ、わためもこれいけないかない？いや、この軽々しく言っちゃいかんね。頑張ろうでも
Then, can Watame go too? No, I shouldn't say it so lightly. Let's do our best, though.
もっと聞いていい？はい。いや、いこ気になることがあってさ
Can I ask more? Yes, sure, there's something I've been curious about...
今までのお靴とかでさ、わためなんか履いてない説が出てるんだけどさ
like with shoes up until now, there's a theory that Watame hasn't been wearing them!
履いてないのかな？
I wonder if she isn't wearing them?
みんな気になってると思う。
I think everyone is curious.
入ってる時と、入ってない時が──履いてない時があった！みんな心臓を──
There are times when they fit, and times when they don't-- There were times when they didn't! Everyone, heart--
履いてない時があるぞ、これ。
There are times when they aren't worn, you know!
どれがどれかは
Which is which...
ご想像にお任せしよう。
I'll leave it to your imagination.
あとはね、なんだ？
And also, what is it?
今、おパンツさま入ってる？ふみママは。
Right now, are you wearing panties, Watame-mama?
入ってるよ。
I am.
何色？え──じゃ、え──そこも、じゃあ、ご想像にお任せということで。
What color? Eh-- Then, eh-- I'll leave that to your imagination as well.
え──じらして、ママのパンチの、今度見とこ。
Eh-- teasing-- Mama's punch, I'll check it out next time.
なんか逆に聞きたいこととかある？
Is there anything you want to ask in reverse?
えっと、あの、この重大発表のために、わためちゃんがすごい頑張って活動して、してて配信外でも忙しいと思ってて。
Um, for this major announcement, Watame-chan has been working so hard, and I thought she's busy even outside of streams.
配信時間もすごいから──体調が、体調が心配。──全然大丈夫だよ！元気！
Because her streaming hours are also amazing-- I'm worried about her health. --It's totally fine! I'm energetic!
よききなまき！／よきつなまき！
Yoki-kinamaki! / Yoki-tsunamaki!
え、ふみママも今忙しいと思うんですけど
Um, Fumi-mama, I think you're busy right now too,
体調大丈夫？
but is your health okay?
あ、元気だよ。
Ah, I'm doing great.
元気、え、いつ寝てんの？ふみママ。
Great? Um, when do you sleep, Fumi-mama?
気になる。うん。
I'm curious. Yeah.
いろんな時間に寝てる。
I sleep at all sorts of times.
いろんな時間？
All sorts of times?
え、大体配信見てくれてるよね、なんか。
Well, you watch my streams most of the time, right?
なんか、ね、寝る時に寝てる、かな？
Well, I sleep when it's time to sleep, I guess?
ちゃんと寝てます。
I sleep properly.
何時間？
How many hours?
日による。7時間とかかな。
Depends on the day. Maybe 7 hours or so.
あ、結構寝てるね！
Ah, you sleep quite a bit!
うん。わたなべも結構それぐらい寝てる。
Yeah. Watame sleeps about that much too.
え、それなら言っちゃった？
Eh, in that case, did you say it?
大丈夫だで？
Is it okay?
ご飯何が好き？
What food do you like?
ご飯はね、タリアッテレとかさ。
For food, um, tagliatelle and stuff.
え、今度一緒に行ってくれる？
Eh, will you go with me next time?
はい、行きたい！
Yes, I'd love to!
行きたい！
I'd love to!
え、じゃ、もう1個聞きたいのがある。
Eh, well, there's one more thing I want to ask.
はい。
Yes.
今後、わためとお絵描きコラボ配信とかする
In the future, what percentage is the possibility
可能性は何％ですか？
of doing a drawing collab stream with Watame?
これ、うわ、どうしよ。
This... whoa, what should I do?
いや、喋るのが苦手…
Well, talking is tough...
そうだよね！
That's right, isn't it!
いや、ハードル高すぎ。
Man, the hurdle is too high.
今日も出てくれるとは思わなかったよ。
I didn't expect you to come out today either.
ダメ元で頼んだ。
I asked you on a whim.
断れないよ、なんかの。
I can't really turn it down, somehow.
あ、呼び出されてんだ、ってそうだった。
Ah, that's right, I was summoned.
あ、そうだった。
Ah, that's right.
断れなかったか。
Couldn't turn it down, huh.
圧に負けたか。
Succumbed to the pressure, huh.
いや、やっぱりね、発表病だからね。
Well, you know, I have presentation phobia after all.
うんうん。
Yeah, yeah.
え、やりたいけどな、また一緒に。
Eh, I'd like to do it again together.
じゃあ、あとで相談しましょう。
Well then, let's discuss it later.
いやだ聞いた！みんな聞いたか？事態取りましたよ！
No way, I heard that! Did everyone hear? I got her consent!
いぇーい！
Yay!
楽しみだなあ。
I'm looking forward to it.
いや、絵教えてほしいんだよ。
Man, I want you to teach me drawing.
何使ってんの？
What do you use?
え、普通にクリップスタジオ。
Um, normally CLIP STUDIO.
何々？フォトショップ？
What, what? Photoshop?
あー、使ったことないんだよなあ。
Ah, I've never used that.
私クリップスタジオ使ったことないから教えてほしい逆に。
I've never used CLIP STUDIO, so teach me instead.
え、教え…。え、でも教えることないよ！
Eh, teach... Eh, but I have nothing to teach!
そんな使いこなせないで。
I can't handle it that well.
でもせっかくね、液タブ買ったから、買ったって言うか買ってもらったんだけどさ。
But, since I bought a pen tablet, or rather had it bought for me...
デュラグね、液タブ使えないんだよね、うまく描けない。
Dual, you know, I can't use the pen tablet well, can't draw properly.
どうしたらいいと思う？
What do you think I should do?
練習やっぱり。
Practice, after all.
あれ？ふみママの霊圧が消えた！
Huh? Fumi-mama's spiritual pressure vanished!
ふみママ！ふみママ！
Fumi-mama! Fumi-mama!
霊圧が消えたー！
Her spiritual pressure is gone!
わ、わためがパンチの色なんて聞いたから、そういうこと！
Wh- Watame asked what color of panties, so that's why!
はい、入ってるか、入ってないか聞いたから、罰せられたってこと？
Yes, because I asked if she's wearing any or not, she got punished?
ふみママが、なんて罪なことを初めてなのに。
Fumi-mama, committing such a sinful act even though it's the first time.
もしわけねえぜ。ないなった。ふみママないなった。
I'm so sorry. She's gone. Fumi-mama is gone.
でもコメントめちゃ草生えてる。みんな模様泣いとる。
But the comments are full of grass. Everyone's crying in patterns.
じゃあ今度コラボしたいね！絵描いてほしいよな。
Well, I want to collab next time! I want her to draw.
ね、みんなもさ、いつも配信とかでさ、ふみママとコラボしねえの？なのって言ってたからさ。
Right, everyone always says in streams and stuff, 'When are you collabing with Fumi-mama?'
やっとなんか今回おしゃべりしてるとこ見せられるって思ったんだけど、ふみママ連れてかれちゃった。
Well, I thought I could finally show us chatting this time, but Fumi-mama got dragged away.
連れてかれちゃった。連ってかれちゃった。
Got dragged away. Got taken away.
あれ？そういえばキーワードももらって、キーワードないなった。
Huh? Come to think of it, I got the keyword, and the keyword is gone.
キーワードないなったということは、今日の重大告知もないなった？ないなった？
If the keyword is gone, does that mean today's major announcement is gone too? Gone?
悲しんで。
Grieving...
でも他にもね、まだね、呼び出されてんだよね。もう。
But also, I'm still being called out by others, you know. Already.
の…お時間というか、なのかな？
Um... Is it time, or something?
読み出しとこっかな？
Shall I start reading?
こないね。
They aren't coming.
じゃ、ちょっと話しながら待ってますかな？
Well then, shall I wait while chatting?
うん、まあ、これも生配信のいいとこですかな。
Yeah, well, this is also a perk of live streaming.
あ、めばちぺいらっしゃい。
Ah, Mebachi-pei, welcome.
はは、はははは。この声は、ははははは。
Haha, hahaha. This voice, hahaha.
ちょっと風邪みたいなこと言わないで。びっくりするから。
Hey, don't say it sounds like a cold. It startles me.
もしがしてん。
Could it be?
バカ垂れの文字、連れてされたってことかー！
Does that mean you brought the letter of the fool?!
そうだよ、フブママの今はバカ垂れ城の中に囚われのみだ。
That's right, Fubu-mama is currently trapped inside Foolish Castle.
そういうことだ！
That's right!
いつ生にバカ垂れ城なんて建ってたんだ！一晩で建ってのか！
When was Foolish Castle built?! Was it built overnight?!
建ってだよ、バカ垂れ共和国にはちゃんと言葉があるんだ！白かったんだけど。
It was! The Republic of Fools has its own words! Though it was white.
あれ？フブちゃんなら並んでるぞ。バカ垂れ城はさあ、人晩で...
Huh? Fubu-chan is lining up. Foolish Castle, overnight...
お、建てるぞ人晩で城なんて。人晩でフブちゃんがやってくれましたん。
Oh, I'll build a castle overnight. Fubu-chan did it overnight for us.
やりました！返してくれよ、フブママ。
We did it! Give it back, Fubu-mama.
フブママより先にまず私たちとやるほうがいいんじゃないか？あ、確かに！そうね、フブママの前にですね。
Wouldn't it be better to do it with us before Fubu-mama? Ah, true! That's right, before Fubu-mama.
最初のね、キーワードをね伝えればならぬという使命があるんだって。
There's a mission that we must convey the first keyword.
何？そう、でもね、やっぱね、ただでは教えないぞと、私たちからのオーダーをクリアできたらあ、キーワード教えてあげるよ。
What? Yeah, but still, we won't teach you for free. If you clear our order, we'll give you the keyword.
ええ？そう、こなくちゃね。
Eh? Yeah, that's more like it.
お題は何だい？ほいほいほい。お題はですね、我々とトークしている時にばれずにノリをを食べよう！だあー！
What's the topic? Hoi hoi hoi. The topic is: eat nori without getting caught while talking with us! Daa!
くだらんね。
How ridiculous.
ま、まあ、まあ、楽勝だな。本当にか？簡単、ルールルールな？ルール簡単だぞ。
Well, well, well, piece of cake. Really? Easy, rules rules? The rules are easy.
ほら、二階さん行って、あの3枚のねノリを用意してもらいました。
Look, go to Nikai-san, and got those 3 sheets of nori prepared.
で、そのうちの1枚でも私たちにバレずに食べたらワタメの勝ち。もし死に、食べてる時に私たちに指摘されたら、そのノリは無効で、そのまま美味しく食べていただきます。はい！
And if you eat even one of them without getting caught by us, Watame wins. If you die, I mean, if you get pointed out by us while eating, that nori is invalid, and you'll eat it deliciously as is. Yes!
トーク終了になったら、1枚でも食べれたか聞くので、そこでジャッジするからね。はい！
When the talk ends, we'll ask if you ate even one, and judge based on that. Yes!
よし、じゃ、やってやんぜ。あ、でも、ちょっと気合を入れるためにいつもの、カブトを...
Alright, then let's do it. Ah, but, to get pumped up, the usual kabuto...
失礼いたします。きゅっ。もう定版になっちゃったよ。将軍が...あ、来た！
Excuse me. Kyu. It's already become the standard. The Shogun... Ah, it's here!
わため将軍。ははは。強そう。ほんとに持ってる？いや、持ってるよ、弱そう。あ、ちょっと弱そうだな。ちゃんとはははは、乾いた笑いして。切れるのかなこれ。いけるのかな。わためだしいつも通りまったりおしゃべりしていきましょう。
Watame Shogun. Hahaha. Looks strong. Do you really have it? No, I have it, looks weak. Ah, looks a bit weak. Right, hahaha, a dry laugh. Can it cut? Can it go? Watame, let's chat leisurely as usual.
はーい！はーい！というわけで、よーい、スタート！
Haii! Haii! So, ready, start!
お、始まりました。じゃ、私たちとトークしてる間にね、ノリを食べれるかどうかってことでございますけども。
Oh, it started. Well, while talking with us, whether you can eat nori is the thing, but...
はい。ちなみに、まあね、あの、夏休みの話題がね、あの、獅子郎のところで出てたんですけども。
Yes. By the way, well, you know, the topic of summer vacation came up at Shishiro's place.
うん。夏休みといえば、バカ垂れでもし夏休みを過ごすなら、なんかしたいこととかありますか？
Yeah. Speaking of summer vacation, if you were to spend summer vacation in Foolish Castle, is there anything you'd want to do?
あ、したいこと？あ、したいこと。なんだろうな？
Ah, what you want to do? Ah, what you want to do. I wonder what?
何がしたい？わためはら。お泊まりで朝までゲームやりてえ！ちょっと寝不足とかしようぜ！ね。
What do you want to do? Watame's belly. Sleepover and play games until morning! Let's get a bit sleep deprived! Right.
出た、ホラーゲーム。お、のことみ食べてた？今。なんだって？食べた？食べた。
There it is, horror games. Oh, were you eating nori? Just now. What? You ate? I ate.
はい、じゃ、ワンダート。白紙がさっきちょっと早かったので、じゃ、次はね、フレアが頑張ってやってください。
Alright, then wandat. Since Shirokami's was a bit early just now, next, Flare, do your best.
はーい。分かりました。お、あらあら。またまたお泊まり、またしたいですね。したいね。
Haii. Understood. Oh, my my. Sleepover again, I'd like to do it again. I'd like to.
他になんかしたいといえばなんだろう？二人は何したい？え、なんだろう、フレア何したい？
What else is there to say you want to do? What do you two want to do? Eh, I wonder, Flare, what do you want to do?
ええ、なんだろうな。でもなんかさ、ドライブとかしたいね、旅行とか温泉とか行きたいね。あ、温泉いいな。ねえ、ゴロゴロしたいな、みんなと。
Eh, I wonder what. But you know, I want to go for a drive, or go on a trip or hot springs. Ah, hot springs sounds nice. Hey, I want to laze around with everyone.
もっとしゃべって 二人、もっとしゃべって。
Let's talk more, you two. Talk more.
なんかね、これ、めっちゃ地味かなんだと、そうだよ！
Oh, wait, this is getting too subtle.
聞き耳立てないじゃん。ねえ、やっぱ自分でさ。
It can't be heard well. Right?
いや、いや、でも、全然もうできできないのでね、もう、私だったら、そうだな。
No, wait, I can't really hear anything.
そうだなあ。
Oh, wait, this is getting too subtle.
まあ、ちょっと難しいけどね。
It's a bit difficult, but...
やっぱ夏がみんなで海とかに行ってね、スイカ割りしたいね。
Wait, everyone goes to the beach and wants to eat watermelon.
したいね。
Do you want to do that?
いいね、したいね。あとバーベキューとかね。
I want to do that. And barbecue!
いいよね、やっぱりね。うん。
Yeah, yeah, it's good. Summer, right?
いい、いい、お肉の匂いとか嗅ぎたいしね、お野菜もね。
Yeah, it's nice to smell good meat, and vegetables too!
お肉のバーベキュー食べたいなあ。美味しいと...うん。
I want to eat good meat.
おうおう、なんだけどね。うーん。おうおう。
I want to do that, but...
ほかはなんだろう、夏といえば？
What else? Speaking of summer...
なんだろうね。夏といえばなんだろう、なんだろう。
What could it be? Summerといえば...なんだろう、なんだろう。
あー、花火とかもしたいね。いいね。
Ah, I'd love to see fireworks too.
あ、いいね、花火もね。
Ah, yeah, fireworks too.
ねえ。
Yeah.
あと、ふぶき、ふりゃー、大丈夫か？これ、わためのって素敵できるか、ちゃんと。
Fubuki, Flare, is this okay?
なんだっけ。私、何か常に、う、う、もぐもぐ言ってる気がするけど。
Wait, I don't know.
え、食べた？、気のせいか。気のせいか。今、食べた、気のせいか。
Wait, did I eat?
あー。気のせいか気のせいか。なるほど。
Ah,気のせいか、気のせいか。なるほど。
気のせいか。また、夏といえば。ホロライブサマー、来年は、あるといいですね。
Wait, summer means... Hololive Summer, hopefully next year.
あ、ねえ。あ、ねえ。
Ah, yeah. Yeah.
やっぱ、二人でちょっとお水、お水着もちょっと見たいぞ。
Wait, I want to see a bit of swimming too.
見た？、ちょっと、見て、これ！
Wait, look at this!
見て？
Look!
なに？、なに？、これ！
What? What is this?
わあ、もう倍倍。な、な、鼻血が出ちゃったよ。
Whoa, it's a swimsuit.
あ、な、な、ちょっと、な、鼻血が。
Whoa, wait.
な、な、鼻血が詰まったの？、そうなだよ。鼻血なんだね。
Wait, my nose is bleeding.
ホロライブサマーというか。バルーンバルーンでお願いして。
Hololive Summer, come on, balloon, balloon!
バルーンバルーンで。え、水着ならわため、どんになるの？、ビキニなんの？、それともなんか、ワンピース型？
Balloon, balloon. If it's a swimsuit, what would Watame be? Bikini?
ビキニ？、ビキニ？、ねえ。
Bikini? Bikini?
どっちがいいの？、ビキニなの？
Wait, which one is better? Bikini?
ワンピースかな？、ワンピース型の可愛いやつ？、じゃあビキニもいいね。
One-piece? A cute one-piece style?
おとな、ねえ。ビキニ着たんだね。
Adult's... Oh, you're wearing a bikini, huh?
まだな、あ、何歳だっけ？わためは。
Wait, how old are you, Watame?
あ、3歳だよ！
I'm 3 years old!
3歳や、ちょっと。だから大人はね。
3 years old? That's a bit... Adults don't wear that.
いいでしょ？
That's fine, right?
無理でしょ！、な、フリルは、フリルは似合いそうだな。でも、スポーティなのは。
Unreasonable! Well, frills... frills would look good, right?
私はね、あんまり着たくないんだよね、あんまりエッチすぎるのは。
I don't really want to be too ecchi.
なんだ。あ、じゃあ可愛い系か。可愛いのがいいね。
Cute ones are better.
フリルいっぱいがいいな。いいね。いいな。
Frills, lots of frills are good. Yeah, good.
あ、ということで。食べたよ。
So, did you eat?
ほんとに？、食べたよ。
Really? You ate?
うそ。一枚しかわかんなかったかも。
Really? I only knew about one.
なんだよ。
How many?
え、なんかさっき食べたかなと思って、食べてなかったしね。難しいぞ。もっとさ、ちゃんとね。
Wait, I thought I ate earlier, but I still had some left.
3枚食べて、1枚もばれて。
I ate three, and one of them I got caught.
3枚食べたの？
You ate three?
そう。2枚目は、ふうたんがね、夏休みの話してるときに食べて。
The second one, I ate while talking about summer vacation.
3枚目は、今ほっぺたに入ってるよ。
The third one is in my cheeks right now.
ずるい！、だってもっと、パリパリ音聞こえなかった。
Wait, I couldn't hear the crunching sound!
ねえ、ちょっと仕切ってたよ。
I was holding back.
仕切ってたよ。
Holding back?
仕切ってたら、それ音聞こえねえだろ。パリパリよ。仕切ってたよ。くやしい！
If you were holding back, the sound would have been heard!
悔しいな、ちょっと、これは。
That's a bit frustrating!
あ、悔しいけど、わための勝ちだから。
Frustrating, but it's Watame's win, so...
やった！、きのワード発表すっか。お願いしまーす。
Yay! Let's announce the keyword.
あ、私やっていいの？
Oh, I'm doing it?
あ、いていいですよ。二人でいいや。
Ah, it's fine, go ahead. Two of you.
じゃあね、キーワードは、だです。
Then the keyword is...
だ？
Da?
だです。だです。ふうみママを今ね、ちょっと、あの、白から出してきてあげるよ。しょうがない。
Da? Is it da?
おっ。
Ah.
最後キーワードでもらおうか。解放しよう。
Keyword, let's receive it. Let's release it.
おう。
Oh.
はい。ということでじゃあね、ちょっとふうみママはまた最初感しますので。
Okay, then, Fuumi-mama will do the first one again, so...
はい。
Yes.
はい、最後のキーワードをもらってください。
Yes, please receive the last keyword.
うん。はい。
Yes.
よかった。
Good.
いようにしゃべれて。
I was able to chat.
ねえ、じゃあ。
Yeah, then let's go.
白に、白に帰ろ、一緒に。
Let's go to the white one together.
わかった。
Got it.
じゃあ先に帰ってっから、わためも後で帰って来いよ。
Let's go back first, and Watame will come back later.
後で来いよ、来て来いよ！
Come later, come on!
うん。
Yeah.
じゃあね。じゃあ、ありがとー！あとで行くねー！
See you later, see you!
はーい！、じゃあねー！、まったねー！
Bye-bye!
おっ、ふみママ帰ってこよかな。
Okay, Mama, let's go back.
ふみママ。
Mama?
おう、帰れ、大丈夫だった！
Oh, Fubuki, it's alright!
だ、大丈夫、大丈夫じゃなかった。
You were alright? It wasn't alright?
大丈夫じゃなかった、何されたん、大丈夫？
It wasn't alright? What happened? Are you okay?
なんか、いろんな、いろいろありました。
Um, various things happened.
いろいろされました。
Various things happened?
ちょっといろんなふみふみさんにもふみふみされました。いろんなことを想像、ちょっと想像かき立てられ、こうしちゃうわ！
Various things happened with Hufu-mama,いろいろなことが想像、ちょっと想像かき立てられ、こうしちゃうわ！
ふふっ。
Haha!
でも、無事でよかった。無事では。
Well, it was good, it was good.
私からキーワードをお伝えしたいと思います。
Let's have Watame tell us the keyword.
はい。
Yes.
キーワードは、
Keyword is...
ぶ。
Bu.
ぶってなんだ？
Bu? What is bu?
ぶ？
Bu?
それでは、キーワードが揃ったと思うので、私は帰ります。
Well, then, since the keywords are ready, I will go back.
ええ、応援してね。
Ah, yeah. Support you.
応援してるよ。
I'm supporting you.
ねぇ、こう…
Hey, like...
二人で一緒に考えましょう。
Let's think about it together.
おっ、考える？
Oh, think?
これ、何だと思う？
What do you think this is?
「６」「こんな」「な…」
"6", "Konna", "Na..."
なんか、「そら」「そらちゃん」
Something like "Sora", "Sora-chan"...
なんかいろいろ考えられるよね。ねえ。
You can think of various things, right? Yeah.
なんか、「アイ」とかローマ字で読んでみたらどうかな。
Like, what if we read "I" or something in romaji?
あい？
"Ai"?
うん、「あい」って読むの？
Yeah, do you read it as "Ai"?
ママ教えてー！
Mama, teach me!
「あい」って読むのかな。「い」？
Do you read it as "Ai"? "I"?
「い」って読むの？
Do you read it as "I"?
なんだ？え、これ漢字は何て読むの？
What is it? Eh, how do you read the kanji for this?
漢字は、ぶって読む。
The kanji is read as "bu".
ぶ？
"Bu"?
お、ライブ？
Oh, "live"?
ライブ？
"Live"?
え？「６」は何て読むの？
Eh? How do you read "6"?
「６」は何て読むの？
How do you read "6"?
私が答えちゃっていいの、これ。
Is it okay if I just answer this?
じゃあ、あとはわためちゃんで考えてみてください。
Well then, please try thinking about it yourself, Watame-chan.
ええー、そんなー！
Ehh, no way!
う、またねー。
Ugh, see you again.
ほみママもありがとう！
Homi Mama, thank you too!
ばくちゃんもありがとう！
Baku-chan, thank you too!
え？これもしやして…
Eh? Could this be...
そ、そ、わためのソロライブ…！？
So- So- Watame's solo live...!?
ソロライブ！？
Solo live!?
え！？
Eh!?
本当に！？
Really!?
ホロライブ四期生の角巻わためです。
I am Tsunomaki Watame from Hololive 4th Generation.
2021年の最初の角巻だいレクトを動画にまとめましたので、ご覧ください。
I've put together the first Tsunomaki Direct of 2021 into a video, so please take a look.
というわけで、角巻わためソロライブの開催が決定しましたーーー！やーーーい！
And so, the holding of Tsunomaki Watame's 1st Solo Live has been decided! Yay!
今日のお知らせを手伝ってくれたみんな、そしてホロライブのみんな、
Everyone who helped with today's announcement, and everyone in Hololive,
え、運営さん、今日応援してくれている、
um, management, everyone supporting us today,
え、みんな、そして今この配信をね、させてくれてるスタッフの方、マネージャーさん、本当にいろんな、いろんな人の力のおかげで、
um, everyone, and the staff and managers who are letting us hold this broadcast right now, truly thanks to the power of so many, many people,
読みます。公演正式タイトル、角巻わためファーストライブ「わためぇ Night Fever!! in Zepp Tokyo」
I will read it. Official concert title: Tsunomaki Watame 1st Live "Watame Night Fever!! in Zepp Tokyo"
Supported by Bushiroad！イエーーーイ！
Supported by Bushiroad! Yay!
声のハッシュタグは、#しゃぶわためソロライブ（※わためがひらがなでソロライブがカタカナです）
The hashtag for your voice is #WatameSoloLive (where "Watame" is in hiragana and "Solo Live" is in katakana).
当日いっぱいツイートしてください。
Please tweet a lot on the day.
そして、会場が Zepp Tokyo！
And the venue is Zepp Tokyo!
Zepp Tokyo、今年でもう閉めちゃうみたいなんですけど、最初で最後ですね、ホロライブでZepp Tokyoに立つやつは。（笑）
It seems Zepp Tokyo is closing down already this year, so this is the first and last time someone from Hololive will stand at Zepp Tokyo. (Haha)
10月12日（火）開場、オープンが17時、夕方の5時。
October 12th (Tue), opening/doors open at 17:00, 5 PM in the evening.
そして配信、配信＆開演かな、スタートが18時、夕方の6時からです。
And broadcast/start, the start is at 18:00, 6 PM in the evening.
で、配信の方がオープンが、5時半、17時30分。ちょっと開場とは30分後になるんですけど、17時30分。
And for the broadcast, the open is at 5:30, 17:30. It'll be 30 minutes after the venue opening, 17:30.
そして、配信の方スタートが18時、6時。これは、会場の方と配信の方両方同じになっています。
And the broadcast start is at 18:00, 6 o'clock. This is the same for both the venue and the broadcast.
会場チケットのスケジュールが
The venue ticket schedule
一次先行 抽選になってるんですけど
is an advance lottery,
受付がなんと 8月19日木曜日の今日の10時から
and the application is from today, Thursday, August 19th, at 10:00 AM,
8月29日日曜日の23時59分まで受付しております
until Sunday, August 29th at 11:59 PM.
ちょっと抽選だからね、あんまり急がなくてもいいかなと思うと
Since it's a lottery, you don't really have to rush, I think.
一般発売が9月25日の土曜日12時から開始です
General sales start on Saturday, September 25th at 12:00 PM.
会場チケット代は 6500円となっております
The venue ticket price is 6,500 yen.
会場チケットや現地での注意事項等詳細はホームページがあるので、
For details such as notes on-site, there's a special website,
特設ホームページをあ、噛んでる！特設ホームページをチェックしてください
so—ah, I stumbled! Please check the special website!
ちょっとご時世的にね、どうなるかまだわかんないんですけど、できれば現地でやりたいなと思っております
Due to the times, we don't know how things will turn out yet, but I'd love to do it on-site if possible.
そして配信の方でもある配信プラットフォームのSPWNでも配信をさせていただきます
And we'll also be streaming on the streaming platform SPWN as well!
8月19日22時10分からこのあとですね、このあと10時から
From August 19th at 10:10 PM—after this, starting at 10:00 PM—
11月12日23時59分まで販売
until November 12th at 11:59 PM, tickets will be on sale.
イベント開催後の一ヶ月後までアーカイブ視聴可能です。
Archive viewing is available until one month after the event.
11月12日まで見れます！アーカイブがあるので視聴可能です
You can watch it until November 12th! Since there's an archive, viewing is possible.
このスポンサーの配信チケット代の方が5000円となっております
The sponsor streaming ticket price is 5,000 yen.
そしてなんと、デジタルフラスタというものが送れるんですけど、
And what's more, you can send digital flower stands!
デジタルフラスタ受付が、2021年8月19日木曜日このあと10時から2021年9月19日日曜日23時59分まで
Digital flower stand applications will be open from 10:00 PM today, Thursday, August 19, 2021, until Sunday, September 19, 2021, at 11:59 PM.
会場から開店までのフラスタなので、デジタルフラスタが掲載されます。
Since flower stands will be displayed from the venue to the opening, digital flower stands will be posted.
詳しくはSPWNのページをチェックしてください！
Please check the SPWN page for details!
あとなんと！なんと！グッズも出ます！
And what's more! What's more! Goods will also be available!
イェーイ！ライブグッズ！
Yay! Live goods!
こちらが応援セットとなっておりまして
This is the support set,
ライブTシャツと、タオルと、ペンライトと、わためのおもしろパリピサングラスです。
which includes the live T-shirt, towel, penlight, and Watame's hilarious party people sunglasses!
これ丸っとセットで1万3000円となっております。
This all-in-one set is 13,000 yen.
このセットをご購入いただきますと、角巻わため複製メッセージ入りミニ色紙キーホルダーをプレゼントします！
If you purchase this set, we will present you with a mini colored paper keyholder with a replicated message from Tsunomaki Watame!
めっちゃいい感じなので、よかったらセットをご購入してみてください。これはライブ前に届くようになっております。
It's super nice, so if you'd like, please consider purchasing the set. This will arrive before the live concert.
あとは、あのバラ売りもさせていただきます。
Also, we will be selling items individually as well.
先行グッズ！1、先行発送グッズ！1、これはライブ前に届くのかな？ライブTシャツ4000円、タオル2500円。
Advance goods! Advance shipping goods 1—will this arrive before the live? Live T-shirt 4,000 yen, towel 2,500 yen.
そして、ペンライト！これファーストライブわためナイトフィーバーって書いてあるんだよね。色も何色かありますので、3500円です。
And the penlight! It says "First Live Watame Night Fever!!" on it. There are several colors too, and it's 3,500 yen.
あとわためのおもしろパリピサングラス！ぜひお揃いにしましょう！これが3000円となっております。
And Watame's hilarious party people sunglasses! Let's match! These are 3,000 yen.
いや、つけてほしいな！ぜひ！これもライブの前に届くようになっているので、よかったらお揃いにしていただけると嬉しいです。
Man, I want you to wear them! Definitely! These are also set to arrive before the live, so I'd be happy if you could match with me.
あとは後日発送のグッズもあります。
Also, there are goods shipped at a later date.
こちらがライブの後、届くグッズになってるんですけど、今回のファーストライブのキービジュアルB2タペストリー3000円。
These are goods that arrive after the live: the First Live key visual B2 tapestry for 3,000 yen.
そして、わためとアイマスク！わためとがグッズになりました！2000円！
And the Watame & Eye Mask! Watame became goods! 2,000 yen!
あとはセットリキーホルダー！わためがライブ当日歌ったセットリストがキーホルダーになって、思い出としてみんなのもとに残ります。よかったら思い出にいかがでしょうか？是非買っていただきたいなと思います。
And the setlist keyholder! The setlist Watame sang on the day of the live becomes a keyholder, staying with everyone as a memory. How about it for a memory? I definitely want you to buy it.
グッズ販売受注期間が8月19日木曜日このあと10時から9月5日日曜日23時59分まで！
The goods sales order period is from 10:00 PM today, Thursday, August 19th, until Sunday, September 5th at 11:59 PM!
日本のユーザーさんはもちろん、海外のわためいとオーバーシープもグッズ申し込みができます！オーバーシープのみんなはギークジャックをチェックしてください！
Japanese users as well as overseas Watamates and overseas fans can apply for goods! Overseas fans, please check GeekJack!
そして、ちょっとサングラス見たいよね？見せるよちょっと写真撮ってあるから見てみて！いや意外といいよね！これをねちょっとつけてもらったから、それもね見ていきましょうかね？
And also, you want to see the sunglasses, right? I'll show you, I took some pictures, so take a look! Man, they're surprisingly nice, right? Someone tried them on for us, so let's take a look at that too, shall we?
なんと！なんと！ベストガール！
What?! What?! Best girl!
やごー、やごー社長がねつけてくれました。
Yagoo... President Yagoo put these on me.
かわいい！
So cute!
みんなもぜひお求めと、やごー社長と角巻社長とそろえちゃいましょう。
Everyone, please get them and match with President Yagoo and President Tsunomaki!
そして、このあとプレミア公開10時から、わため元のオリジナルソング「mayday, mayday」が投稿されるので、
Also, starting at 10 PM tonight, my original song "mayday, mayday" will premiere,
10時からもぜひ見てください。動画見てください。
so please be sure to check it out at 10 PM!
そのあと今日の24時、0時、8月20日0時、今日の24時に
And right after that, today at 24:00—midnight, August 20th at midnight—
「mayday, mayday」がなんとiTunesさんとかで買えます！よかったらいっぱい聞いてください。買って下さいお願いします。
"mayday, mayday" will be available on iTunes and other platforms! Please listen to it lots and buy it, please!
あとは24時からもね、メンバーでお話しをしたいなと思っているので、よかったらメンバーに入ってくださる方はお話ししましょう。
Also, starting at midnight, I'd like to chat with members, so if you'd like to join membership, let's chat!
いやぁ情報もりだくさんだって分かった？なんか日付とかいっぱい言ったけど大丈夫だったかな？
Phew, that's a lot of info, right? I said a lot of dates, I hope that was okay.
ちょっとね、情報これからもね更新いろいろされると思うので概要欄にもねいっぱい書いてあると思うのでチェックしてみてください。
I'm sure there will be more updates coming, so it'll all be in the description box, please check it out.
あと特設サイトがねめちゃいい感じなのでよかったら見てね。
Also, the special site looks amazing, so please check it out if you'd like!
じゃあ最後はわためのあの曲で締めたいと思います！曖昧ショコラテ！
Now, I'd like to close with that one song! Ai-mai Chocolate!
ああ、またやっちまった
Ah, I messed up again.
隠してたわけじゃないの
It's not like I was hiding it.
きっとただ言ってないだけ
I just didn't mention it.
だって恥ずかしいんだもん
Because it's too embarrassing.
ああ、またやっちまった
Ah, I messed up again.
隠してたわけじゃないの
It's not like I was hiding it.
きっとただ言ってないだけ
I just didn't mention it.
だって恥ずかしいんだもん
Because it's too embarrassing.
みーんな！最高に盛り上がっていきましょう！
Everyone! Let's get hyped to the max!
ライブの予行練習だと思って楽しんでいってください！
Think of this as a live rehearsal and have fun!
意外と寂しんぼ
Surprisingly lonely,
意外と甘えんぼ
surprisingly needy,
意外と慌てんぼ
surprisingly hasty,
意外と照れ屋
surprisingly shy.
丸い飛行雲
A round plane trail,
飛び出したカップケーキ
an overflowing cupcake.
3回目コンディショナー
Conditioning for the third time,
余るパズルピース
an extra puzzle piece.
ふわふわ浮かぶ夢見心地
Floating lightly like a dream.
ひとつひとつ数えておやすみなさい
Counting them one by one, good night.
密かに芽生えたこのキモチ
This secret feeling growing inside me.
まっすぐ見つめないで
Don't stare straight at me.
なんだっけ…？
What was it again...?
言葉にしちゃうときっとそうじゃない
Putting it into words isn't quite right.
照れちゃうだけおちゃらかしちゃうじゃない
I just get shy and goof around.
本当の本当は隠したいんじゃないの
It's not like I want to hide my true feelings.
もそうじゃないのにさ
Sheesh, it's not like that at all!
曖昧なんじゃないの
It's not vague at all.
この気持ちは間違いじゃない
This feeling is definitely not wrong.
指切りげんまん
Pinky swear.
かなりドジっ子で優柔不断でも
Even if I'm quite clumsy and indecisive,
絶対に毎日会いに来てくれるよね？
you'll still come see me every day without fail, right?
本来臆病で案外泣き虫
I'm naturally timid and a bit of a crybaby,
全然変わらず元来キミばかり
but nothing has changed, it's always been all about you.
当たり前のようにキュンてしちゃう
My heart flutters as if it's the most natural thing,
キミがいないとガッカリしちゃう
and without you, I feel so let down.
本当の本当にショッポリしちゃうわ
It honestly makes me feel so down and sad.
会いたくなっちゃうなあ後悔ばっかりしちゃう
I end up wanting to see you so much, only to regret it.
このココロも勇気出しちゃえ
Let's be brave with this heart too!
この指とまれ
Come join this circle.
歌うことが大好きなひとりの1匹の羊が
A single sheep who loves to sing so much
こんなにたくさんの羊に囲まれて
is surrounded by so many sheep like this,
大きな大きな夢ができて
and has made such a big, big dream come true.
今回その夢に向かう第一歩だと思っています！
I believe this is the very first step toward that dream!
よかったらみんな一緒に
If you'd like, everyone, together...
その一歩を
Take that step
踏み出してください 見つけてね
and find me!
弱いところ気付かれたり
Even if my weak points are noticed,
寂しがりごと包まれたり
or my loneliness is embraced,
いつまでも笑い合ったり
always laughing together,
たまにはムっと喧嘩をしたり
or sometimes getting into a huffy fight—
ずっとずっとそばにいてほしい
I want you by my side forever.
約束だぞ！
Promise me!
いっちゃった
I blurted it out...
もしかしたら運命かも
Maybe this is destiny.
赤い糸が見えちゃうかも
Maybe the red thread is visible.
本当の本当はバレてるのかも
Maybe my true feelings are already exposed.
目合わせられないかも
Maybe I can't even look you in the eye.
曖昧なんてない
It's not ambiguous at all,
たくさん私を見てて
look at me a lot!
読み切った！
I figured you out!
ありがとう！待ってるよ！
Thank you! I'll be waiting!
Tsunomaki Watame 1st Live わためぇ Night Fever!! in Zepp Tokyo 2021.10.12
Tsunomaki Watame 1st Live "Watame Night Fever!!" in Zepp Tokyo (Oct. 12, 2021)
重大告知 …わため呼び出し?!
[Major Announcement: Watame Summoned?!]